Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we're talking about something that I think a lot of people
我是Kathryn，今天我们聊的话题，我觉得很多人
experience especially with certain things like peanuts and cats.
都经历过，尤其是对花生和猫这类东西。
So what are we talking about?
那我们在聊什么呢？
That's right.
没错。
Today we are talking about allergies.
今天我们聊的是过敏。
So that means that we have a problem with maybe cats.
也就是说，我们可能对猫有问题。
They make us sick or with certain foods.
它们让我们不舒服，或者对某些食物。
Like a lot of people who are allergic to milk actually.
比如很多人其实对牛奶过敏。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to talk about a couple of these allergies and symptoms.
所以我们要聊聊几种过敏和症状。
So why don't we have a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
那我们不如先听听对话，一会儿再回来。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I keep sneezing and my eyes are all watery.
我一直打喷嚏，眼睛还水汪汪的。
What's wrong with me?
我这是怎么了？
Wow, you're not dying, are you?
哇，你不会是要死了吧？
It looks like you have a cold.
看起来你像是感冒了。
You should take some medicine.
你应该吃点药。
I don't think it's a cold.
我觉得不是感冒。
I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk.
只要我离办公桌几步远，我就感觉没事。
Maybe we should put you into quarantine.
也许我们该把你隔离起来。
Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy.
说正经的，我觉得你可能是过敏了。
An allergy?
过敏？
I never thought about that.
我从没想过这个。
I don't think I'm allergic to pollen though and I'm desensitized to bee stings after being
不过我觉得我不是对花粉过敏，而且被蜜蜂蜇了那么多次后，
stung so many times.
我已经脱敏了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Ow!
哎哟！
Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
你为什么拿花生扔我？
Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts.
就是看看你对花生过不过敏。
I guess not.
看来不过敏。
Not funny.
一点都不好笑。
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
我可能会过敏性休克。
Okay, my bad.
好吧，我的错。
How about dust?
那灰尘呢？
My office is full of it.
我办公室到处都是。
Yes, the whole office is dusty yet I only feel affected near our desks.
是啊，整个办公室都是灰，但我只在咱们办公桌附近才有感觉。
You brought your cat into the office?
你把猫带到办公室了？
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffle's birthday today.
是啊，今天是Snuffle先生的生日。
I didn't want him to be alone on his special day.
我不想让它在这个特别的日子孤单。
Ah, put it away.
啊，把它弄走。
I guess we found the problem.
我想我们找到问题了。
You're allergic to cats.
你对猫过敏。
Alright so now let's take a look at vocab on Language Takeaway.
好了，现在我们来看看“语言小贴士”里的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Alright so Marco we have a number of things that might happen if you're feeling like you're
好的，Marco，如果你感觉对什么东西过敏，可能会发生一些情况，
allergic to something.
我们有好几个要讲。
The first one is my eyes are all watery.
第一个是“我的眼睛水汪汪的”。
Okay, so your eyes get watery and that means you start to have a lot of water, a lot of
好的，所以你的眼睛变得水汪汪，意思是眼睛里开始有很多水，
tears in your eyes.
很多眼泪。
That's right but you're not sad, you're not crying.
没错，但你不是难过，不是在哭。
It's just that you have this reaction that you cannot control and the water maybe comes
只是你有了这种无法控制的反应，水可能会
down from your eyes.
从眼睛里流下来。
Right, usually your eyes get wet and watery, itchy, red, so a lot of that.
对，通常眼睛会变得湿湿的、水汪汪的、发痒、发红，就是这样。
There's another thing too, this happens a lot.
还有一件事，这也很常见。
You feel like you can't stop sneezing.
你感觉停不下来打喷嚏。
To sneeze.
打喷嚏。
A sneeze is something you do when the air comes out of your nose.
打喷嚏就是空气从鼻子里出来的动作。
Out of your nose, out of your mouth, out of everywhere.
从鼻子、从嘴巴、从所有地方出来。
Yeah and you can't control it and sometimes it's very, very strong.
是啊，而且你控制不了，有时候还非常剧烈。
You move your head but it's something that you do when you're allergic to something like
你会甩头，但这是你对某些东西过敏时的反应，比如
a cat or a flower but also maybe when you smell something very, some spice like hot
猫或花，但也可能是闻到很刺激的东西，比如辣椒。
pepper.
对，或者生病时，比如感冒。
Yeah, or when you're sick, when you have a cold.
没错。
That's right.
And so his friend says that maybe they should put him into quarantine.
然后他的朋友说也许该把他隔离起来。
Alright now this is a joke.
好了，这是个玩笑。
If you have allergies you don't have to go to quarantine but quarantine is very serious.
如果你过敏，不需要去隔离，但隔离是很严肃的事。
It's a place where people go when they have a dangerous or very infectious disease and
那是人们得了危险或传染性很强的疾病时去的地方，
quarantine means that no one else can come in and you cannot go out.
隔离意味着别人不能进来，你也不能出去。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So I think when they had the pig flu, the swine flu, many people were put into quarantine
所以我觉得猪流感那会儿，很多人被隔离起来，
to make sure they didn't give it to someone else.
以确保他们不会传染给别人。
That's right.
没错。
So usually in quarantine you have to wait until you can prove that you're not sick anymore
所以通常隔离期间，你得等到能证明自己不再生病，
and then you get to leave.
然后才能离开。
That's right.
没错。
Alright, so they were talking about maybe the options of what he's allergic to.
好了，所以他们聊了聊他可能对什么过敏。
He says I don't think I'm allergic to pollen.
他说“我觉得我不是对花粉过敏”。
So what is pollen and where does it come from?
那么花粉是什么，它从哪里来？
Alright, now pollen is actually a very common allergy and pollen comes from flowers.
好的，花粉其实是一种非常常见的过敏原，花粉来自花朵。
It's kind of like a special dust or special kind of thing that you see on flowers that
它有点像一种特殊的灰尘或特殊的东西，你会在花朵上看到它，
gets blown away.
然后被风吹走。
So when it's springtime many people suffer from allergies because there's a lot more
所以在春天，很多人会过敏，因为空气中
pollen in the air.
有更多的花粉。
So it's that little dust, usually sometimes yellow, that you can find on flowers and this
就是那种小灰尘，通常是黄色的，你可以在花朵上找到它，
is actually what butterflies and bees look for.
而这正是蝴蝶和蜜蜂寻找的东西。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And then he talked about, well, he's not allergic to bees and his friend threw a peanut at him
然后他谈到，嗯，他对蜜蜂不过敏，他的朋友朝他扔了一颗花生，
but he said it in a very strange way.
但他用一种很奇怪的方式说的。
He said, why did you chuck that peanut at me?
他说，你为什么朝我扔那颗花生？
To chuck.
扔（chuck）。
Alright, to chuck.
好的，扔（chuck）。
Now this is a very spoken English way of saying something.
这是一种非常口语化的英语表达方式。
To chuck means to throw.
“To chuck”意思是扔。
So like, Marco, why did you chuck that pillow at me?
比如，Marco，你为什么朝我扔那个枕头？
That was mean.
那太坏了。
Alright, so to chuck is to throw but usually to throw something strongly.
好的，所以“to chuck”就是扔，但通常指用力扔东西。
So as you said, it's very spoken English.
就像你说的，这是非常口语化的英语。
It's not really proper to actually write it or say it to someone in a formal occasion.
在正式场合写出来或对别人说不太合适。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So you wouldn't say this in your English exam but you could say this with your friends.
所以你不会在英语考试中说这个词，但可以和朋友们说。
Okay.
好的。
So to chuck something.
所以“to chuck something”。
So that's all the vocab we have for you.
这就是我们为你准备的所有词汇。
Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again.
我们不如回去再听一遍对话吧。
Oh, I feel terrible.
哦，我感觉糟透了。
I keep sneezing and my eyes are all watery.
我一直打喷嚏，眼睛也泪汪汪的。
What's wrong with me?
我怎么了？
Wow, you're not dying, are you?
哇，你不会是要死了吧？
It looks like you have a cold.
看起来你感冒了。
You should take some medicine.
你应该吃点药。
I don't think it's a cold.
我不觉得是感冒。
I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk.
如果我离开桌子几步远，我就感觉很好。
Maybe we should put you into quarantine.
也许我们应该把你隔离起来。
Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy.
说正经的，我觉得你可能过敏了。
An allergy?
过敏？
I never thought about that.
我从没想过这个。
I don't think I'm allergic to pollen though and I'm desensitized to bee stings after being
不过我觉得我对花粉不过敏，而且被蜜蜂蜇了这么多次后，
stung so many times.
我已经脱敏了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Ow!
哎哟！
Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
你为什么朝我扔那颗花生？
Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts.
只是检查一下你对花生过不过敏。
I guess not.
看来不过敏。
Not funny.
不好笑。
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
我可能会过敏性休克。
Okay, my bad.
好吧，我的错。
How about dust?
那灰尘呢？
This office is full of it.
这办公室到处都是灰尘。
Yes, the whole office is dusty yet I only feel affected near our desks.
是的，整个办公室都是灰尘，但我只在我们的桌子附近有感觉。
You brought your cat into the office?
你把你的猫带到办公室了？
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffle's birthday today.
是啊，今天是Snuffle先生的生日。
I didn't want him to be alone on his special day.
我不想让它在这个特别的日子孤单。
Ah, put it away!
啊，把它拿走！
I guess we found the problem.
我想我们找到问题了。
You're allergic to cats.
你对猫过敏。
Alright we're back so now it's time for Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在是流利度训练时间。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Alright, now we heard a very difficult word later on in the dialogue.
好的，我们在对话后面听到了一个很难的词。
Jim said, not funny, I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Jim说：“不好笑，我可能会过敏性休克。”
Right.
对。
Alright, so this phrase, to go into shock is very important.
好的，所以这个短语“to go into shock”非常重要。
Go into shock.
进入休克状态。
Now what does it mean to go into shock?
那么“进入休克状态”是什么意思？
Well shock is something, especially anaphylactic shock, which means that I think you stop breathing
休克是一种情况，尤其是过敏性休克，意思是你的身体基本停止运作，
because your body basically shuts down and your throat tightens so you can't breathe.
喉咙收紧，无法呼吸。
But to go into shock means that your body will kind of stop doing its normal functions.
但“进入休克状态”意味着你的身体会停止正常功能。
For example, if you fall in very, very, very cold water, your body goes into shock.
比如，如果你掉进非常非常冷的水里，你的身体会进入休克状态。
And this is something that is a physical reaction.
这是一种身体反应。
You see it all the time in movies I think when a nurse or a doctor or someone yells
你在电影里经常看到，护士或医生大喊
he's going into shock, right?
“他休克了”，对吧？
That's right and they have to get the paddles and beep.
没错，他们得拿电击板，然后“哔”一声。
So that's what it means when you go into shock but you use this verb.
这就是“进入休克状态”的意思，但你要用这个动词。
You go into shock.
你进入休克状态。
He's going into shock.
他休克了。
That's right, doctor, he's gone into shock.
没错，医生，他休克了。
And well he said, okay, I'm sorry, my bad.
然后他说：“好吧，对不起，我的错。”
He said my bad.
他说“my bad”。
What is my bad?
“my bad”是什么意思？
Alright, my bad is another phrase that comes from spoken English so be careful with how
好的，“my bad”是另一个来自英语口语的短语，所以使用时要小心。
you use it.
你使用它。
This is something you can use with your friends.
这是你可以和朋友一起用的表达。
My bad is a way of saying my fault or excuse me, that was my mistake.
“My bad”是一种说“我的错”或“抱歉，是我的失误”的方式。
So if you do something wrong and you say, oh, I'm sorry, that was my mistake, you can
所以如果你做错了事，说“哦，对不起，是我的错”，你可以
just say, oh, my bad.
直接说“哦，my bad”。
That's right.
没错。
Or Jerry, can we go outside for a second?
或者杰瑞，我们能出去一下吗？
I have to talk to you.
我得跟你谈谈。
I mean, Marco, oh, my bad.
我是说，马可，哦，my bad。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
That means, you know, my fault.
那意思是，你知道，我的错。
I'm sorry, I've made a mistake.
对不起，我犯了个错误。
But this is very colloquial and I think it's very juvenile, right?
但这非常口语化，而且我觉得很孩子气，对吧？
I think younger people use this, my bad.
我觉得年轻人会用这个，“my bad”。
My bad.
“My bad”。
Yeah, it's younger, yeah.
是的，更年轻化，嗯。
That's a younger, alright.
那是更年轻化的，好吧。
And for our last phrase, when Jim was talking about maybe being allergic to pollen or he
至于我们最后一个短语，当吉姆在说可能对花粉过敏时，或者他
said I'm desensitized to bee stings.
说“我对蜜蜂蜇伤脱敏了”。
Alright, so desensitized, you should know automatically that prefix D means not, alright?
好的，所以“desensitized”，你应该自动知道前缀“de-”表示“不”，对吧？
So it's negative.
所以它是否定的。
I'm desensitized means that I'm not sensitive to, alright?
“I'm desensitized”意思是“我对……不敏感”，对吧？
That means that, you know, if I get stung by a bee, like me, it gets big and red and
那意味着，你知道，如果我被蜜蜂蜇了，像我这样，它会变得又大又红，
it hurts.
而且疼。
Right.
对。
But this person, he doesn't have a reaction.
但这个人，他没有反应。
He's desensitized.
他脱敏了。
So there's no reaction.
所以没有反应。
There's no red.
没有红肿。
There's no swelling.
没有肿胀。
I think you see it a lot for people that maybe live in an area where there are a lot of mosquitoes.
我觉得你经常看到这种情况，比如住在蚊子很多地区的人。
And if we go there, we're going to get bitten and it's going to be itchy.
如果我们去那里，会被咬，而且会很痒。
But people who live there, they've been bitten so many times that they probably don't even
但住在那里的人，他们被咬了太多次，可能甚至
feel it or probably don't even get bitten anymore.
感觉不到，或者可能根本不再被咬了。
They desensitize.
他们脱敏了。
That's right.
没错。
Or you could say that I'm desensitized to loud noises.
或者你可以说“我对噪音脱敏了”。
Okay.
好的。
I live in a city and there's a metro near my apartment.
我住在城市里，公寓附近有地铁。
I can hear it.
我能听到它。
It's very loud.
声音很大。
And so I'm desensitized to the noise.
所以我对噪音脱敏了。
That means I don't really notice it anymore.
那意味着我不再真正注意到它了。
It doesn't bother me.
它不会打扰我。
Right.
对。
Very good.
非常好。
So that's all the vocab and phrases we've prepared for you today.
这就是我们今天为你准备的所有词汇和短语。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍这段对话。
Oh, I feel terrible.
哦，我感觉糟透了。
I keep sneezing and my eyes are all watery.
我一直在打喷嚏，眼睛也泪汪汪的。
What's wrong with me?
我怎么了？
Wow.
哇。
You're not dying, are you?
你不会是要死了吧？
It looks like you have a cold.
看起来你感冒了。
You should take some medicine.
你应该吃点药。
I don't think it's a cold.
我不觉得是感冒。
I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk.
如果我离开办公桌几英尺远，我就感觉很好。
Maybe we should put you into quarantine.
也许我们应该把你隔离起来。
Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy.
说正经的，我觉得你可能过敏了。
An allergy?
过敏？
I never thought about that.
我从没想过这个。
I don't think I'm allergic to pollen, though, and I'm desensitized to bee stings after being
不过我觉得我对花粉不过敏，而且被蜜蜂蜇了那么多次后，我对蜇伤
stung so many times.
已经脱敏了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Ow!
哎哟！
Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
你为什么朝我扔那颗花生？
Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts.
只是检查一下你对花生过不过敏。
I guess not.
我猜不过敏。
Not funny.
不好笑。
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
我可能会过敏性休克。
Okay, my bad.
好吧，my bad。
How about dust?
灰尘呢？
This office is full of it.
这办公室到处都是灰尘。
Yes, the whole office is dusty, yet I only feel affected near our desks.
是的，整个办公室都是灰尘，但我只在我们的办公桌附近有感觉。
You brought your cat into the office?
你把你的猫带到办公室了？
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffle's birthday today.
是啊，今天是斯纳福先生的生日。
I didn't want him to be alone on his special day.
我不想让它在这个特别的日子孤单。
Put it away!
把它收起来！
I guess we found the problem.
我想我们找到问题了。
You're allergic to cats.
你对猫过敏。
Alright, so speaking about allergies, we always talk about the common ones like pollen, dust,
好的，说到过敏，我们总是会提到常见的那些，比如花粉、灰尘，
and you also mentioned about food, like somebody who cannot drink milk.
你还提到了食物，比如有人不能喝牛奶。
They're allergic to milk.
他们对牛奶过敏。
That's right.
没错。
We have a special name for this, actually.
实际上，我们对此有一个专门的名称。
Someone who cannot drink milk or dairy products like ice cream is called lactose intolerant.
不能喝牛奶或吃冰淇淋等乳制品的人被称为乳糖不耐受。
So if you're lactose intolerant, it means that your stomach is very upset after you
所以如果你乳糖不耐受，意味着你吃了乳制品后胃会很不舒服，
have dairy products because lactose is basically dairy.
因为乳糖基本上就是乳制品。
And there are some people also who are allergic to seafood, for example, fish or shrimp or
还有一些人对海鲜过敏，比如鱼、虾或
any type of seafood.
任何类型的海鲜。
That's right.
没错。
And also people who are allergic to gluten.
还有人对麸质过敏。
Now, gluten is a very common product that is found in breads and cereal, things like
麸质是一种很常见的成分，存在于面包和谷物等食物中，
that.
类似的东西。
And so people who have an allergy to gluten actually have to change their diet quite a
所以对麸质过敏的人必须大幅改变他们的饮食。
bit.
Yeah, they have to look for things that are gluten-free, which is very hard because apparently
是的，他们得找无麸质的食物，这很难，因为显然
it's in everything.
麸质几乎无处不在。
That's right.
没错。
So if you have one of these allergies, you can find dairy-free on a box or gluten-free
所以如果你有这些过敏之一，你可以在包装上找到“无乳制品”或“无麸质”
on the box.
的标签。
And specialty food stores will have these labels.
特色食品店会有这些标签。
And so are you allergic to anything?
那么你对什么东西过敏吗？
No, not really.
不，基本上没有。
Sometimes here in China, I feel like I'm a little bit allergic.
有时在中国，我感觉自己有点过敏。
I have allergies when the seasons change.
换季的时候我会过敏。
But at home, no.
但在家里，不会。
I have no allergies.
我没有任何过敏。
No allergies.
没有过敏。
No, me neither.
不，我也没有。
And I'm very lucky, I think, because I can't imagine if I had an allergy like to peanuts
我觉得自己很幸运，因为我无法想象如果我对花生
or to seafood, which not only would be a shame because you can't have these foods, but if
或海鲜过敏，那不仅可惜，因为你不能吃这些食物，而且如果
you accidentally have it, it could be life-threatening.
不小心吃了，可能会危及生命。
That's right.
没错。
Like my dad, who is allergic to bees, would go into anaphylactic shock if he were stung.
比如我爸爸对蜜蜂过敏，如果被蜇了，他会过敏性休克。
And so you have to be very careful because you never know when you'll have an accident
所以你必须非常小心，因为你永远不知道什么时候会发生
like that.
这样的意外。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So this is an interesting topic.
所以这是个有趣的话题。
Maybe you guys want to share if you are allergic to anything.
也许你们想分享一下自己对什么东西过敏。
Maybe you are allergic to certain types of foods, chemicals.
也许你对某些类型的食物、化学物质过敏。
Some people are allergic to certain types of shampoo, for example.
比如有些人对某些类型的洗发水过敏。
Or fabrics like cotton.
或者对棉花等织物过敏。
So if you want to share with us, let us know at our website EnglishPod.com.
所以如果你想和我们分享，请在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye!
再见！